Hi, my name is Rachel and I'm the owner of austinstylewatch.com street fashion site, and I'm also a freelance fashion reporter, and today we're going to talk about how to choose the right neck line for your body.
So first we're going to go over a couple of different types of necklines.
First one I'm wearing here is a strapless.
Second we're going to talk about here is a v-neck. It "v's" down. Third we're going to talk about is a boat neck, and that just kind of cuts from shoulder to shoulder; sort of that '80's kind of look.
And the final one we're going to talk about today is a turtle neck.
It goes high up on the neck.
So, these different cuts flatter different types of head shapes, face shapes and bust lines.
So, we're going to talk about what's kind of advantageous for each type.
If you have a long face something like a turtle neck can help make that long face look a little more round.
If you have a very round face, a v-neck could kind of help take away from that and bring some length down to it.
So, the next thing we're going to talk about, I talked about face, now we're going to talk about bust. So, if you're large busted things that work for you are going to be strapless, and also the boat neck because the look of the neck attracts to the chest but doesn't accentuate or minimize it.
It works well for the area.
If you're a large busted woman, and you have to watch out on this that you don't get it a cut a little too low, but a v-neck can compliment the bust very well.
You just have to make sure you don't get anything that cuts down so far that you're having a lot of cleavage showing.
The v-neck also works really well to minimize the shoulders.
If you have a broad shoulder, it kind of always looks like you're wearing shoulder pads, a v-neck can take the eye down the center of you, rather than so much on the shoulders.
Finally, we're going to talk a little more on the turtle neck, and the turtle neck's another nice one that's a conservative choice for large busted women because it helps cover up a little more.
So, you get that look there.
All right, so, to review you have a v-neck, boat neck, turtle neck and strapless.
And that's how to match the best neckline with your body.